<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Jack Baty</title>
<link>https://baty.blog</link>
<description>Jack Baty's Weblog</description>
	<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/16/We-cannot-know-what-moti.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 05:53:36 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/16/We-cannot-know-what-moti.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>A frequent mistake we make is to believe that we can know the motivations of others.</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/15/From-Readwise-to-org-roa.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 06:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/15/From-Readwise-to-org-roa.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>Yesterday, I canceled my <a href="https://readwise.io">Readwise</a> subscription because, although it's cool, I wasn't getting much tangible value from it. Today, I discovered  <code>org-roam-node-random</code>  and it's kind of good enough as a replacement.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Charge me more for software but less for services</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Charge-me-more-for-softw.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 14:56:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Charge-me-more-for-softw.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Charge-me-more-for-softw.html">Charge me more for software but less for services</a></h3>



<p>I would like pricing pressure for software to go up, but for subscriptions to go down. I'll happily pay $250 for a great app, but don't want to pay more than $12/year for a read-it-later service or newsletter or magazine. The number of apps I <i>need</i> is rather low. The number services, news, and entertainment options I need approaches infinity and I just don't have the budget for that.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Trying-to-cancel-subscri.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 11:53:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Trying-to-cancel-subscri.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>Suffering a serious bout of Subscription Fatigue today, so I decided to cancel all non-critical subscriptions. All but one of them were "Annual" plans. Canceling those doesn't feel quite as good as I'd hoped.</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Checking in after a couple months of blogging with Tinderbox</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Checking-in-after-a-coup.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 04:23:13 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Checking-in-after-a-coup.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/14/Checking-in-after-a-coup.html">Checking in after a couple months of blogging with Tinderbox</a></h3>



	<img src="https://baty.blog/img/small/tinderboxicon.png" alt="Checking in after a couple months of blogging with Tinderbox" class="sideImage">

<p>Early last November, in <a href="posts/2021/11/04/Welcome-back-I-guess.html">Welcome back, I guess</a>, I wrote this:</p>
	<blockquote>If I'm being honest, I'll admit that this is just an excuse to play with some old toys and experiment with new ones. </blockquote>
	<blockquote>See also: Sometimes I change my mind</blockquote>

<p>Let's look at how it's going with my Blogging With Tinderbox experiment.</p>
<p>First, it's been a ton of fun wrangling <a href="http://www.eastgate.com/Tinderbox/">Tinderbox</a> into generating a nice-looking blog that fits my particular way of blogging. I was inspired after trying Dave Winer's <a href="http://drummer.scripting.com">Drummer</a> blogging tool. Tinderbox is ridiculously flexible and powerful and fun, and made this blog possible.</p>
<p>I love outliners, and this site is built using Tinderbox's powerful version of outliner. All the <a href="https://logseq.com">cool</a> <a href="http://drummer.scripting.com">new</a> <a href="https://roamresearch.com">kids</a> are using outlines, too.</p>
<p>Keeping my "Daybook" type entries in the same Tinderbox file as my blog posts is pretty great. It lets me see everything all at once. I can link, collect, arrange, and analyze <i>everything</i> I write, whether public or private. This is not a small thing, it will likely become more useful over time.</p>
<p>So, I'll be sticking with Tinderbox for my daily notes blogging, then? Not so fast.</p>
<p>The mechanisms for generating this blog out of Tinderbox are fragile. More than once in the past week, I've broken large portions of the site after making what I thought to be a minor change to a template or Agent. Debugging it took quite some time. It makes me nervous.</p>
<p>Links are powerful but strange in Tinderbox. For a simple blog, I don't need powerful. I need them to be easily created and simple to edit. I don't find them to be.</p>
<p>The elephant in the room is Emacs, and, more specifically, Org mode. You see, as much as I like managing and processing notes in Tinderbox, I don't love <i>writing</i> in it. Notes in Tinderbox are rich text. Sure, technically you can have them behave as if they're Markdown, but doing so is definitely swimming upstream. Tinderbox does a good job of converting rich notes into HTML, and even offers control over how formatting is rendered. It's all very clever. However, it's a long way from plain text, and I prefer plain text for writing. And I very much enjoy writing plain text in Emacs.</p>
<p>I haven't decided yet which way I'll be taking this blog. For the moment, I like the results so much that I'm happy using Tinderbox. But I feel the pull of Emacs and the simplicity of Org mode and Markdown. I'm still hoping to find a way to have both.</p>





    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Combining RSS feeds for everything</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/11/Combining-RSS-feeds-for-.html</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 08:14:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/11/Combining-RSS-feeds-for-.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/11/Combining-RSS-feeds-for-.html">Combining RSS feeds for everything</a></h3>



<p>There is an ongoing conflict between my love of trying new blogging/publishing tools and the idea of having One True Blog™. The first is for me and the second is for readers.</p>
<p>I had a thought this morning. What if I could aggregate all of my sites into a single RSS feed? There are a few approaches to this, but what I've decided to try is cross-posting everything to <a href="https://copingmechanism.com">Coping Mechanism</a>. The idea is that Coping Mechanism would grab the posts from my other sites and combine them into one giant blog whose RSS feed encapsulates everything.</p>
<p>I'm testing this with a couple of WordPress plugins: <a href="https://www.wprssaggregator.com">WP RSS Aggregator</a> and its <a href="https://www.wprssaggregator.com/extension/feed-to-post/">Feed to Post</a> add-on.</p>
<p>I'll let you know if it works. If it does, those of you with an interest in following my various experiments will have a handy, single RSS feed to subscribe to. Meanwhile, I can continue writing all over the place.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/My-basement-studio-.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 19:11:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/My-basement-studio-.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[




<figure>
		<img src="https://baty.blog/img/2022/20220110-R0002015.jpg" alt="It's almost like a studio. Almost." class="postimage">
</figure>






    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/The-Leica-MP-is-heading-.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 04:48:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/The-Leica-MP-is-heading-.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[




<figure>
		<img src="https://baty.blog/img/2022/2021-07-09-R0001361.jpg" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<p>The rewind knob on my Leica MP is difficult to turn when film is loaded. Rewinding the M3 works like butter, so I wrote Leica about it. They've suggested I send the camera in to the repair center in New Jersey so they can take a look. Off it goes. 😭</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/Good-morning.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 04:27:27 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/10/Good-morning.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[




<figure>
		<img src="https://baty.blog/img/2022/20220105-Q1000103.jpg" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<p>Good morning. It's 4:30 am and my ears are numb from our walk this morning. This post should get pushed to Micro.blog. Let's see!</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Should I crosspost to Micro.blog?</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Should-I-crosspost-to-Mi.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 9 Jan 2022 06:49:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Should-I-crosspost-to-Mi.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Should-I-crosspost-to-Mi.html">Should I crosspost to Micro.blog?</a></h3>



<p>I find myself missing <a href="https://micro.blog">Micro.blog</a>. The community there is unmatched by any that I've found elsewhere. I sometimes miss the occasional interaction around my posts. </p>
<p>Living alone on my blog has been a deliberate choice. I wanted to make blogging less performative. After all, I write for myself, first, and if others get something from it, then yay. But that's a side effect.</p>
<p>Except it gets lonely. Not many people actually visit this site. If I'm being honest, I enjoy sharing things. It's nice to be heard, at least a little.</p>
<p>So, yesterday I built a new RSS feed here that I think will work for Micro.blog. Now I just need to decide if and when to turn it on.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Programming note: We're now officially at baty.blog</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Programming-note-We-re-n.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 9 Jan 2022 05:02:00 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Programming-note-We-re-n.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/09/Programming-note-We-re-n.html">Programming note: We're now officially at baty.blog</a></h3>



	<img src="https://baty.blog/img/small/meta-splat.png" alt="Programming note: We're now officially at baty.blog" class="sideImage">

<p>I'd never intended for the new daily notes site to live at <a href="http://daily.baty.net">daily.baty.net</a>. That was for testing. It stuck around longer than I would have preferred, but I've finally made the move and replaced the Ghost blog with this Tinderbox-managed site at https://baty.blog.</p>
<p>It's being pushed to both the old and new domains for the time being. At some point over the next few days I'll pull the plug on the old domain.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Leica-M11-Specs.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jan 2022 18:02:01 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Leica-M11-Specs.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>Given that the <a href="https://hmeye.files.wordpress.com/2022/01/open-leica_m11_technical_data_en.pdf">spec sheet of the new Leica M11</a> has been leaked a week early, I thought I'd check out the Leica forums. I recently sold my M10-R, so of course I'm interested in what's next for Leica. My god, how I hate speculation. The discussions are boring and useless and I'm going to stop reading them. The good news is that, based on the specs, I see no pressing need for owning an M11. </p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>New RSS feed for all posts</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/New-RSS-feed-for-all-pos.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jan 2022 16:17:41 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/New-RSS-feed-for-all-pos.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/New-RSS-feed-for-all-pos.html">New RSS feed for all posts</a></h3>



<p>I built this site's RSS feed so that it only includes the big daily posts, one per day, but that post is appended to throughout the day. This feels right for most people. It doesn't work if I want to crosspost, though, since the first published version is usually only me saying "Good morning" and that would be it.</p>
<p>I've added a second RSS feed, <a href="https://baty.blog/allposts.xml">allposts.xml</a>, which includes each individual post, independent of the containing day's post. I'll use this feed for crossposting. To keep things from becoming too noisy, I've added an attribute, "Crosspost" which defaults to false. Only those posts with $Crosspost==true are included in the feed. Clear as mud?</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Moxie-s-first-impression.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jan 2022 12:10:14 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Moxie-s-first-impression.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>What a great post by Moxie Marlinspike. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Instead of storing the data on-chain, NFTs instead contain a URL that points to the data. What surprised me about the standards was that there’s no hash commitment for the data located at the URL. Looking at many of the NFTs on popular marketplaces being sold for tens, hundreds, or millions of dollars, that URL often just points to some VPS running Apache somewhere. Anyone with access to that machine, anyone who buys that domain name in the future, or anyone who compromises that machine can change the image, title, description, etc for the NFT to whatever they’d like at any time (regardless of whether or not they “own” the token). There’s nothing in the NFT spec that tells you what the image “should” be, or even allows you to confirm whether something is the “correct” image.</p>
<figcaption>Moxie Marlinspike <cite><a href="https://moxie.org/2022/01/07/web3-first-impressions.html">My first impressions of web3</a></cite></figcaption>
</blockquote>
<p>I'll happily live out my life in web1, thank you. You kids have fun, though!</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Shooting film when I'm in the mood</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Shooting-film-when-I-m-i.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jan 2022 06:16:07 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Shooting-film-when-I-m-i.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Shooting-film-when-I-m-i.html">Shooting film when I'm in the mood</a></h3>



<p>Over the past several years, my interest in shooting film has regularly ebbed and flowed. This fluctuation wouldn't be a problem if the frequency and amplitude weren't so high. My brain does this thing where it decides, usually after a successful roll or inspiring blog post, that I'm now going to "shoot only film from now on!" This is immediately followed by the purchase of supporting cameras or other gear.</p>
<p>A short time later, I tire of waiting to finish a roll, even though when I'm in film mode I claim that "waiting is a feature". The digital cameras come out and I start wondering why I bother with the hassle of film, when digital is "better", faster, and cheaper. I should sell off most of the film gear, shutter the darkroom, and just learn how to make decent inkjet prints instead.</p>
<p>And then, I finally finish that roll, process it, scan it, and make a couple of darkroom prints. Wow! This is so cool and fun and I love the images and I love having the negatives neatly organized in binders on my shelves for future generations of scholars and historians. (ha!).</p>
<p>So, what I'm saying is that I enjoy both film and digital. I should learn that about myself. I should build processes around both, as needed, and stop trying to decide which I want to do exclusively and realize that it all depends upon my mood.</p>




    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title></title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Stop-changing.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 8 Jan 2022 06:09:12 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/08/Stop-changing.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[





<p>They say as you get older that you want things to stop changing (Do they say that?) and I'm starting to believe them.</p>



    ]]></description>

</item>
<item>
<title>Photo processing workflow update, Jan 2022</title>
<link>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/07/Photo-processing-workflo.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 7 Jan 2022 05:26:13 -0500</pubDate>
<guid>https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/07/Photo-processing-workflo.html</guid>
<description><![CDATA[



	<h3><a href="https://baty.blog/posts/2022/01/07/Photo-processing-workflo.html">Photo processing workflow update, Jan 2022</a></h3>



	<img src="https://baty.blog/img/small/photomechanic.png" alt="Photo processing workflow update, Jan 2022" class="sideImage">

<p>TL;DR: I'm back to a combination of <a href="https://www.captureone.com/en">Capture One Pro</a> and <a href="https://home.camerabits.com/tour-photo-mechanic/">Photo Mechanic Plus</a>, with a dash of Apple Photos.</p>
<p>I continue to waffle on which app to use for which portion of my photography workflow. Most recently, I'd considered <a href="posts/2022/01/03/Apple-Photos-vs-Lightroo.html">Apple Photos vs Lightroom Classic as photo library</a>. This was fueled by my desire to keep my library and my editing tool separate. LrC is probably the best all-around solution, and is the closest thing we have to an "industry standard". But, I prefer Capture One Pro for RAW processing. </p>
<p>Capture One's catalog is mediocre, so I've built a new catalog of all my photos using  Photo Mechanic (Plus). This lets me work with "Sessions" in C1, which I much prefer. I wish PM's UI for browsing its catalog was prettier, even if that meant it was less powerful. Still, it's quite fast and powerful.</p>
<p>Apple Photos is great for sharing and just having my photos with me on all devices, so I've added "Export to Apple Photos" as a final step.</p>
<p>Here's my current workflow for digital camera images.</p>
<p>In Capture One:</p>
<ul><li> Import from card into Capture One session's Import folder</li>
<li> Delete anything I don't like (ruthlessly)</li>
<li> Edit any keepers</li>
<li> Export a finished JPEG into the same folder as original image</li></ul>
<p>In Photo Mechanic</p>
<ul><li> View the import folder in Photo Mechanic</li>
<li> Rate, keyword, and caption each image</li>
<li> Move all images into dated folders and add to PM catalog</li>
<li> Export full-size version of any starred images to Apple Photos</li>
<li> Share and upload as needed</li></ul>
<p>This means I spend only enough time in Capture One to edit select images and "burn" JPEG copies. Then it's off to Photo Mechanic for metadata and organization. Then out to Apple Photos for sharing with family and any other apps. The "big catalog" is Photo Mechanic.</p>





    ]]></description>

</item>

</channel>

</rss>