<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
<title>Jack Baty Daily</title>
<link>https://daily.baty.net</link>
<description>Daily notes by Jack Baty</description>
	<item>
<title>Tuesday, January 4, 2022</title>
<link>posts/2022/01/04.html</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 4 Jan 2022 06:35:54 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220104-Messy.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/04/Quote-An-unprofessional-.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/04/Meditation-and-Metta.html">#</a></span> <p>I have been trying a meditation practice using Sam Harris' "<a href="https://wakingup.com">Waking Up</a>" course. Today, he had us try "Metta" which means "loving-kindness". What he had me do was wordlessly wish someone I care about, "May you be happy. May you be peaceful. May you be free from suffering." I am amazed at how good that made me feel. I might like this meditation stuff.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220104-R0002003-Edit.jpg" alt="The Family: Leica Q2 Monochrom, MP, and SL2-S. I am very fortunate." class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/04/The-Leica-Family.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220104-L1000740.jpg" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/04/Quote-Jarod-Lanier-on-se.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/04/Boring-solutions.html">#</a></span> <p>If the solution you've chosen isn't boring you've probably chosen the wrong thing.</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2022/01/04/Big-screens-are-bad-for-.html">Big screens are bad for me</a></h3>

<section>


	<p>I use a 32-inch monitor on my desk at home and I love it. I can do one big thing like, say, editing photos with room to spare. Or, I can do a bunch of small things all at once. </p>
<p>It's that second part that gets me. Most of the time I can see the windows of at least a half-dozen different apps at once. This has been causing me some consternation. I find myself flitting about between apps and windows and tasks, simply because I happen to notice something somewhere on the screen.</p>
<p>I've noticed that whenever I detach the MBP and work on only the "little" 14-inch screen, I feel much more focused. Calmer, even. It's happening right now as I type this. The Tinderbox note window I'm typing in takes up most of the screen, leaving me to relax and pay attention to what I'm doing.</p>
<p>Of course it depends on the task. Launching Lightroom Classic is a harsh reminder of the limited the screen real estate here. If I needed an IDE and browser and terminal side-by-side all the time I'd feel cramped. But for general computing stuff, email, blogging, etc. Smaller may be better.</p>
	
</section>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2022/01/04.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monday, January 3, 2022</title>
<link>posts/2022/01/03.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jan 2022 04:35:56 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/03/Good-morning-.html">#</a></span> <p>Good morning. It's 4:40 am the first Monday of the year. If I had a job, that would probably have more significance. Still thinking about weekly projects but my Rails app from a couple weeks ago seems to have been a failure and that is discouraging me.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220103-stench-of-honolulu.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/03/Jack-Handy-Quote-about-s.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/03/Change-to-movies-listing.html">#</a></span> <p>I've updated the <a href="movies.html">Movies</a> listing to use a table rather than a list based on each note's $DisplayExpression. There's now a conditional in the Tinderbox export template for the Movies agent. This feels a little fragile, but it works. I've also added an icon (<img src="/img/icons/note-icon.png" class="icon">) if a movie has a review or notes. This avoids wasted clicks if there's nothing to see.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.nethttps://photos.smugmug.com/Blog-Photos/i-6XBHFL6/0/c36af669/XL/20220103-Q1000001-XL.jpg" alt="Mirror self-portrait. First photo with new Leica Q2 Monochrom" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/03/Leica-Q2-Monochrom.html">#</a></span>  

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2022/01/03/Apple-Photos-vs-Lightroo.html">Apple Photos vs Lightroom Classic as photo library</a></h3>

<section>


	<p>I have nearly 100,000 photos in Adobe Lightroom (Classic). Lightroom is only useful on my Mac and is rather clunky to use as a library. The new Lightroom is nicer, and syncs everywhere, but I don't want to rely on Adobe's cloud.</p>
<p>I'm thinking of using Apple Photos as my library. It's on all my devices automatically. It's simple and looks nice enough. Nearly every photo-related app can access the library directly, obviating the need to "share" from app to app. My family uses it, so shared albums are easy for them to find. Plus, it has face and object recognition and really good OS integration. Photos is also the most likely app I'll still be using in 10+ years.</p>
<p>Using Photos means that rather than importing photos taken on my phone into Lightroom, I export photos I've processed with Lightroom into Photos. </p>
<p>The big downside here is that my LrC library only contains locally-imported photos, and my phone contains all my iPhone photos plus just the images I've exported from LrC. I have no one canonical place with <i>everything</i>. I can't decide if this matters.</p>
<p>I could configure Lightroom on my phone to automatically sync photos back into my library, but then I have to be careful about re-importing to Photos so I don't end up with duplicates. This has happened before. </p>
<p>I may also try PhotoSync again to see if I can find a way to have the best of both worlds.</p>
	
</section>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2022/01/03.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sunday, January 2, 2022</title>
<link>posts/2022/01/02.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 2 Jan 2022 07:29:16 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/02/Good-morning-What-kind-o.html">#</a></span> <p>Good morning. It's 7:35 am because Alice slept until 6:45. I hardly know what to do with myself after nearly eight ours of sleep. Let's see what kind of day this can be.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20211227-R0001993.jpg" alt="A good regular reminder, so I keep it pinned to my bulletin board." class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/02/Thomas-Paine-quote.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/02/I-still-miss-the-APO-Sum.html">#</a></span> <p>I took a photo of the dog against a bright background using the Leica SL2-S with the Sigma 24-70 f/2.8. The sigma is a fine lens, but it (literally) pales in comparison with the native Leica primes. Alice was lacking in contrast and sharpness due to the slight flaring and CA that occurs with the Sigma. I've taken nearly identical photos with the APO Summicron-SL 35mm and they were bright, sharp, and contrasty. I miss that lens.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/02/What-s-up-guys-.html">#</a></span> <p>Whatever I end up doing next, It's not going to be what Eric Floberg is making excellent fun of in this video:</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/HHsMHHKJ8Us" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>yeesh.</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2022/01/02/But-is-it-too-complicate.html">But is it too complicated?</a></h3>

<section>


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/tinderboxicon.png" alt="But is it too complicated?" class="sideImage">

	<p>Publishing this blog using <a href="https://eastgate.com/Tinderbox">Tinderbox</a> is certainly complex, but is it also too complicated?</p>
<p>There are many moving parts: agents, rules, expressions, action code, attributes, and so on. But to simply publish this post, all I do is hit return, type some words, and click a button. Not complicated at all. However, if I decide to change something, or if I change something by accident, all hell might break loose. </p>
<p>Publishing is simple here, but running the show is pretty complicated. Still, this setup is fun, lightweight, super flexible, and ultimately renders a static site. I'm thinking it's a fair balance.</p>
<p><b>Update:</b> Dave Rogers<a href="https://nice-marmot.net/Archives/2022/January_2022.html#note_798"> posted a note</a> about complexity and Tinderbox and it's made me feel a bit better. His blog, <a href="https://nice-marmot.net">Nice Marmot</a>, is one of the things that inspired me to dive back to Tinderbox for personal blogging. I'm glad I did. Thanks, Dave!</p>
	
</section>







	<h3><a href="posts/2022/01/02/Hobonichi-2022.html">Hobonichi 2022</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220102-R0001995.jpg" alt="Hobonichis on my journal shelf" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/hobonichi.jpg" alt="Hobonichi 2022" class="sideImage">

	<p>I bought my first <a href="https://www.1101.com/store/techo/en/about/">Hobonichi Techo</a> in 2013, and I've used one every year since. One of my favorite things in any new year is copying over events from last year's calendar into the new one. Birthdays, anniversaries, etc. It's a much better feeling than something like waiting for Facebook to tell me when to pay attention to someone.</p>
<p>Another thing I do every January is plan on going all-in with the Techo. Todos, appointments, notes, lists, everything should go in that lovely book with its wonderful Tomoe River paper. But then I worry about it being too small. With big plans to use analog tools even more this year, will the little Hobonichi be too limiting?</p>
<p>The answer to that question has always been, "No." Most of those Techos on my shelf are at least half empty. I'd wager there aren't more than a couple dozen pages where I could have used more room.</p>
<p>What this all means is that I have not learned my lesson and will be once again diving right into the plans to use the Techo for everything. The difference this time is that I'm not going to worry about running out of room. I hope that will mean that I do run out of room, because wouldn't that be awesome.</p>

	
</section>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2022/01/02.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Saturday, January 1, 2022</title>
<link>posts/2022/01/01.html</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 1 Jan 2022 05:42:43 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/01/Good-morning-2022.html">#</a></span> <p>Good morning. It's 5:45 am on the first day of 2022. Or, as I like to call it, "New Folders Day".</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2022/20220101-RideOutTheClock.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/01/Quote-Riding-out-the-clo.html">#</a></span> <p>When I think about diving back into the workforce I try to remember that quote.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/01/NIfty-File-Lists.html">#</a></span> <p><a href="https://www.publicspace.net/NiftyFileLists/index.html">Nifty File Lists</a> looks like it could be handy, especially in a <a href="https://forum.eastgate.com/t/moving-file-names-and-metadata-into-tinderbox/5330">Tinderbox context</a>.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2022/01/01/Some-site-changes-today.html">#</a></span> <p>I made a few small changes around here this morning: <a href="changelog/Don-t-include-partial-im.html">Don't include partial image paths in templates</a>, <a href="changelog/Added-link-to-Movie-temp.html">Added link to Movie template</a>, and <a href="changelog/Replaced-header-backgrou.html">Replaced header background image with primary theme color</a>.</p> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2022/01/01.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Friday, December 31, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/31.html</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 04:43:31 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/31/And-that-was-2021.html">#</a></span> <p>2021 was a year of personal exploration that didn't really end up going anywhere. Maybe I can take what I learned this past year and apply it to something useful in 2022.</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/31/My-Leica-Camera-Timeline.html">My Leica Camera Timeline</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211231-LeicaTimeline.png" alt="My Leica Camera Timeline (<a href="https://jackbaty.smugmug.com/Blog-Photos/i-3FPvD8W/A">full size</a>)" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/leica.png" alt="My Leica Camera Timeline" class="sideImage">

	<p>I bought my first Leica, an M6 TTL in 2004. I've bought and sold a number of them since then. I currently own an M3, M6, MP, Q2 Monochrom, and SL2-S. In the above timeline, film cameras are green and digital cameras are yellow. Can you spot which type I tend to keep longer? The dates should be mostly accurate. There are some conflicting notes on my old blog, but they occur in 2012 which is the year I really messed things up during a platform change, so I've used my Lightroom catalog and Flickr data when in doubt. I also have some notes suggesting that I've owned two Leica M7s but I don't remember that at all.</p>
<p>The future for me probably holds a beat-up original M10 at some point after the M11 is released. Prices should get more reasonable then. I'll probably end up selling the M6 to fund it or something like it. Or maybe I'll sell the MP one day, although the thought makes me shudder. I've had friends say to me, "Never sell a Leica. You always regret selling a Leica." I should probably heed their advice.</p>
	
</section>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/31/Seeing-my-notes.html">Seeing my notes</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/map2009.png" alt="Tinderbox project map from 2009" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<p>While looking up information for creating <a href="posts/2021/12/31/My-Leica-Camera-Timeline.html">My Leica Camera Timeline</a>, I ended up in a bunch of old Tinderbox documents, dating back to 2008. </p>
<p>The above image shows a project map from my 2009 daybook Tinderbox file. It's so easy to understand what was going on when I can see my notes visually like that. But I also have the same information in a simple outline. </p>
<img src="/img/2021/20211231-Outline2009.png">
<p>I know I talk a lot about how plain text is so great and future proof, and it is. But it's best for <i>searching</i> and less useful for understanding. At least for me.</p>
	
</section>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/31/Automattic-vs-Ghost---it.html">#</a></span> <p>I prefer creating content in Ghost to WordPress. It's faster, simpler, and generally cleaner. However, I don't love the people behind Ghost. Their goals don't align with mine. Most of the time, who cares? But sometimes I <i>do</i> care. Then I saw <a href="https://initialcharge.net/2021/12/mullenweg-protocol/">Mike Rockwell's post</a> with quotes from Matt Mullenweg and it reminded me that I much prefer Automattic's <i>attitude</i> which is one reason I've reverted <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a> to WordPress.</p> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/31.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Thursday, December 30, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/30.html</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 04:24:55 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/30/Good-morning.html">#</a></span> <p>Good morning. It's 4:30 am. What a lovely walk through the fresh snow this morning.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/olympia-tracing.jpg" alt="Yep, still have 2 blogs" class="sideImage">

<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/30/Yep-still-have-2-blogs.html">#</a></span> <p>I hate the fact that I still have two (active) blogs. Moving <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a> to a more blog-friendly template made things confusing. And now this Tinderbox blog is getting so nice that the problem is even worse. They're now both very similar. Too similar.  I think I have to put <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a> back as a photography-focused blog with an overwrought template, just to differentiate it from this one. I'm also considering moving this blog to baty.blog and eliminating the Ghost instance running there. And I kind of want to bring back the <a href="http://rudimentarylathe.org">rudimentarylathe.org</a> domain. The elephant in the room, of course, is that you just know I'll change things again in a week or a month or a year. Then what? Broken links, RSS noise, confusion, etc. Anyone reading care to chime in?</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/30/Weight-logging-with-Tind.html">Weight logging with Tinderbox</a></h3>

<section>


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/tinderboxicon.png" alt="Weight logging with Tinderbox" class="sideImage">

	<p><i>Note: This was originally posted over at <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a> but I thought it belonged here instead</i>.</p>
<p>I kept a “daybook” using <a href="http://www.eastgate.com/Tinderbox/">Tinderbox</a> for years. I drifted away from Tinderbox for a while after becoming infatuated with Linux or iOS or other “cross-platform” systems. Right now, I’m back with a vengeance.</p>
<p>While rebuilding my Daybook, I wanted to make logging my weight easier. It’s not like it was difficult, but I wanted to tweak it.</p>
<p>Tinderbox is an outliner, so my weight entries are collected under a “Weight Log” node. It looked like this (I obviously wasn’t consistent with tracking last year).</p>
<img src="/img/2021/20211230-weight-log.png">
<p>The weight is stored in a numeric User Attribute called, surprisingly, “Weight”. The outline shows a custom “DisplayFormat” so that it reads nicely:</p>
<p><code>$Weight + " pounds on " + format($StartDate,"MM D")</code></p>
<p>To enter a new weight, I’d select an existing item in the outline, hit Return to create a new note, type in the weight, hit Return to save the note, then use the mouse to click the “Weight” attribute and re-enter the weight there. So much clicking!  😀.</p>
<p>What I wanted to do was to type the weight once in the note’s Name and have the Weight attribute populated automatically. Tinderbox notes can have “Rules” which are commands that run periodically and can update a note’s attributes based on just about any criteria. I could have created a rule that set the Weight based on the Name, but that seemed like overkill since this only ever needs to happen once per note.</p>
<p>With some help from Michael Becker, I think I’ve got it. (You should check out his <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AQCp8tVRJSg&list=PL6MVDtSfcKxd2XLpenMAd9H4VknDyn6oz">video series on Mastering Tinderbox</a> for all sorts of great Tinderbox content.)</p>
<p>There’s an OnAdd action which sets the Prototype, Date, and Name of the note. (Setting the Name of the new note to “Enter Weight” is a nice touch.)</p>
<p><code>$Prototype="pWeightLogEntry";$Date|=date(today);if($Name=="untitled"){$Name="Enter Weight"};</code></p>
<p>Then, the new note gets a Rule (via the pWeightLogEntry Prototype) which sets the Weight attribute based on the value of Name:</p>

<code><pre>
$Weight|=$Name;
if($Weight>0){
$Name=$Date("l");
$RuleDisabled=true};</pre></code>

<p>The trick here is setting $RuleDisabled=true. What this does is force the Rule to run only once, which is all I need. I wasn’t aware of the $RuleDisabled attribute, so thanks to Michael for that tip.</p>
<p>Now, to add a new Weight Log entry, I hit Return, type my weight, and hit Return again. Couldn’t be any easier! On my Daybooks “Dashboard” I can graph my weight over time, like so…</p>
<img src="/img/2021/20211230-weight.png">
<p>For those of you unfamiliar with Tinderbox, I’m sorry if I made too many assumptions here. Explaining Tinderbox can be an entire job in itself!</p>
	
</section>






<div class="postNoTitle">


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/leica.png" alt="Shot 2 rolls of film" class="sideImage">

<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/30/Shot-2-rolls-of-film.html">#</a></span> <p>I'm reviewing my lens situation. The Leica 35mm Summilux-M ASPH is a pricey lens, so I'm rethinking it. I bought the Summilux for the M10-R, which I've now sold. I figured this was fine, since I could still use it on both the film Ms and the SL2-S. On the other hand, I've really been missing that APO Summicron-SL 35 . I've been considering trading the Summilux M for the Summicron SL. That would leave a 35mm gap in my M kit. Since it's film, I can get away with a Zeiss or Voigtlander, right? So I shot a roll with the 50mm Summilux-M and then with the 35 to see how they feel on film. Well, they're both terrific. So now I don't know what to do. For now, I'm just going to shoot more and ignore the entire problem.</p> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/30.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Wednesday, December 29, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/29.html</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 04:23:06 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/29/Good-morning.html">#</a></span> <p>Year: ▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓▓░ 99%</p>

<p>Good morning. It's 4:25 am and let's try and not waste an entire day. <i>Another</i> entire day.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/29/Tinderbox-Watch-Folders.html">#</a></span> <p><a href="https://eastgate.com/Tinderbox">Tinderbox</a> has a feature that watches a folder in the Finder, Apple Notes, <a href="https://www.devontechnologies.com/apps/devonthink">DEVONthink</a>, and even <a href="https://tot.rocks">Tot</a>. It doesn't sync both ways, but it will import new notes from within those watched places and make new notes in a Tinderbox outline. This makes it easy to add notes to my Tinderbox file from a phone or iPad. It wouldn't be too much trouble to just copy and paste, but watched folders make it even easier.</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/29/Today-agent-in-Tinderbox.html">Today agent in Tinderbox</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211229-today.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<p>I have a top-level Agent in my Tinderbox daybook named "Today". All it does is collect notes using a <code>$Date=date(today);</code> query.  Given that I'm putting both blog content and personal logging into the document, the Today container is a handy way to see everything going on today. I'll probably modify it to use a date attribute so I can easily jump to any day and see what I wrote then. Neat.</p>
<p><b>Update</b>: I did change the agent query to use my $Date attribute, like this:</p>
<p><code>$Date=$Date(agent);</code></p>
<p>I also changed the agent's $DisplayExpression to reflect the day: </p>
<p><code>"Created " + if($Date==date(today)){"Today"} else {$Date.format("l");}</code></p>
<p>So now I just set the $Date attribute of the "Today" agent to any date and it collects all the dated content created that day.</p>
	
</section>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/29/Fixed-RSS-date.html">#</a></span> <p>I think I've fixed the RSS feed's date. The feed template didn't have a "pubDate" element at all. This probably happened when changing the feed template to do daily posts instead of one item per post. Anyway, sorry about that. Let me know if anything looks amiss.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211229-personal-mba.png" alt="I feel seen" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/29/A-man-and-his-methods.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


	<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/small//img/small/tinderboxicon.png" alt="Tinderbox or go to a play" class="sideImage">

<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/29/Tinderbox-or-go-to-a-pla.html">#</a></span> <p><a href="https://eastgate.com/Tinderbox">Tinderbox</a> is an expensive piece of software, no doubt. You know how people dismiss spending $5 for an app, since "it costs the same as a Starbucks coffee."? Well, I like to think of Tinderbox as no more expensive than buying tickets to a play...a really good play that performs continually all day, every day, and helps me get stuff done and stay organized and publish a blog and...and...and. It's actually cheap, when you think of it that way. 😀 <a href="https://fondoftea.com/#2021-12-29%20-%20Wednesday">Alex's note</a> made me think of this.</p> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/29/The-beginnings-of-my-Tin.html">The beginnings of my Tinderbox 2022 Dashboard</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211229-dash.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<p>I'm rebuilding my Tinderbox "Dashboard" for the new year. I neglected the whole Daybook last year but I'm determined to not let that happen this year.</p>
<p>The dashboard is a Tinderbox "Map" view littered with agents showing various summary and aggregate information from the entire document.</p>
<p>In the "Days remaining this year" note, I used to only show the resulting integer. I'd forgotten that in map view, notes can visually plot the values of various attributes (as in the Weight Graph, shown). The note's edict (an edict is like a rule, but runs less often) sets the note's $Subtitle to the number of days remaining in the year, like so:</p>
<p><code>$Subtitle=days(date("today"),date("12/31/2021 6:00 PM"))</code></p>
<p>I cheated in the screenshot using "42" because with only 2 days left this year, it doesn't make for a great demo. The inspector for that note looks like this:</p>
<img src="/img/2021/20211229-inspector.png">
<p>The note uses the built-in "Dashboard" prototype to make things prettier.</p>
<p>The note's $DisplayExpression is simply <code>$Name + ": " + $Subtitle</code></p>
<p>Neat, eh?</p>
	
</section>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/29.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tuesday, December 28, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/28.html</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 28 Dec 2021 04:34:36 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Good-Morning.html">#</a></span> <p>Good morning. It's 5:04 am and today I'm going to focus on getting my Daybook logs in order. I keep a "Captain's Log", which is just notes like "Paid the mortgage". I also log books, movies, my weight, and meals.</p>
 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211228-permanent-record.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Edward-Snowden-quote.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Two-blogs.html">#</a></span> <p>Looking over at <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a>, it's obvious I still have two blogs. I don't see a way out of this.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Weight-logging-with-Tind.html">#</a></span> <p>I wrote up how I'm <a href="https://copingmechanism.com/2021/weight-logging-with-tinderbox/">logging my weight in Tinderbox</a>. </p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Movie-logs.html">#</a></span> <p>Well now I've gone and added my Daybook's <a href="/movies.html">Movie Log</a> as part of the blog export. It's a little fancy so I'll write up details later.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/A-Response-To-Have-Singl.html">#</a></span> <blockquote class="quoteback" darkmode="" data-title="A Response To 'Have Single-Page Apps Ruined the Web?'" data-author="" cite="https://htmx.org/essays/a-response-to-rich-harris/">
<p>This is, unfortunately, part of the culture of front end development right now: sky-high levels of complexity are tolerated in application frameworks, in build tool chains, in deployment models and so on, and, when problems arise due to all this complexity, more complexity is often offered as the answer.</p>
<footer><cite> <a href="https://htmx.org/essays/a-response-to-rich-harris/">https://htmx.org/essays/a-response-to-rich-harris/</a></cite></footer>
</blockquote><script note="" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/Blogger-Peer-Review/quotebacks@1/quoteback.js"></script> 

</div>







	<h3><a href="posts/2021/12/28/The-M10-R-has-left-the-b.html">The M10-R has left the building</a></h3>

<section>

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211222-L1000681.jpg" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


	<p>I've used some version of Leica M camera since 2004. I love them so much that I recently purchased a brand new MP film camera, which is awesome. Only a month ago, I was finally able to get the latest digital M, the M10-R. Surprisingly, I didn't love it. I wanted to love it. I <i>thought</i> I'd love it. I didn't. </p>
<p>The M10-R was going to be my everyday carry camera. That didn't work out. </p>
<p>The M is a slow, manual-focus, deliberate camera. It's not really suited for just having around taking snaps. It only focuses down to like three feet. Manual focus means that every shot requires two hands. It's very very expensive, so letting it just dangle around my neck while not paying attention to it is a terrible idea. I love the <i>idea</i> of a digital M, but the execution leaves me wanting.</p>
<p>So I'm going back to a Q2 Monochrom :).</p>

	
</section>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/28/Reluctant-to-post-in-Wor.html">#</a></span> <p>It's weird how much I avoid clicking the "New Post" button in WordPress, yet I love just hitting Return and adding to the outline here. It's the same thing, but different, ya know?</p> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/28.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Monday, December 27, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/27.html</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Dec 2021 05:15:57 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/olympia-tracing.jpg" alt="The first drawing I made with an iPad and Apple Pencil" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/I-like-sitting-here-and-.html">#</a></span> <p>At times, I feel embarrassed about sitting here and writing for so long every day. There are so many other, more "productive" things I could (should?) be doing. But I love doing this. I love writing and sharing the things I'm thinking about. I love sitting in front of this beautiful monitor with this amazing keyboard attached to the best computer I've ever owned, and just typing.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211227-spiders.png" alt="" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/David-Wong-Quote.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/I-want-only-one-blog.html">#</a></span> <p>I want only one blog. How the hell will I ever make that happen? Tinderbox is awesome but blogging with it requires a lot of setup and probably long-term fiddling. WordPress can do anything but feels clumsy. Ghost is slick and fast but feels focused on "building an audience" and doesn't have comments or stats. Hugo is cool and fast and I get to use Emacs, but it's also very <i>separate</i> from the actual rendered content. TiddlyWiki isn't for blogging, even though it can be coerced into it. I'll never be able to choose just one option and stick with it for more than, say 72 hours. For example right now I have 3 of my sites loaded in tabs and am weighing pros and cons of each and determining if any of them could be The One. I hate this.</p>
<p>...1 hour later...</p>
<p>I think I'll focus on <a href="https://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a> for now. I'm also considering either copying these daily notes into a daily post on <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a>, or not publishing to the daily blog at all. I'll just use Tinderbox for writing and organizing, then use WordPress for publishing. I do like the <a href="http://daily.baty.net">daily.baty.net</a> blog output, though. But do I want to keep working at it so hard?</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/I-got-to-use-my-new-snow.html">#</a></span> <p>It snowed overnight, so I finally got to use my new snowblower. Worked like butter. Clearing the driveway is now basically just walking back and forth for a few minutes.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/About-that-M10-R.html">#</a></span> <p>I continue to feel that perhaps the Leica M10-R is not the right camera for the way I take photos. This disturbs me a little, because I <i>want</i> it to be The One.</p>
<p>I've boxed up the camera and plan to list it on <a href="http://fredmiranda.com">fredmiranda.com</a> later today. Let's see if I chicken out again.</p>
<p>Update: It's for sale: <a href="https://www.fredmiranda.com/forum/topic/1734952/0?nc=1#15809485">https://www.fredmiranda.com/forum/topic/1734952/0?nc=1#15809485</a></p>
 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/DEVONthink-is-back.html">#</a></span> <p>I didn't think I'd want to install DEVONthink on my new Mac. I've been all "but files and folders can do everything!" I was wrong. DTP makes collecting, storing, organizing, and analyzing files and text so easy that I feel like I still need it. Maybe not "need", but definitely <i>want</i>.</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211227-screen.png" alt="My window for writing in Tinderbox" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/27/Getting-comfy-with-Tinde.html">#</a></span> <p>This sure is a comfy way to write.</p> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/27.html</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Sunday, December 26, 2021</title>
<link>posts/2021/12/26.html</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 26 Dec 2021 07:23:21 -0500</pubDate>
<description><![CDATA[



<div class="postNoTitle">

<figure>
		<img src="https://daily.baty.net/img/2021/20211225-L1000071-Edit-2.jpg" alt="Sage. Leica M10-R. 35mm Summilux-M FLE" class="postimage">
</figure>


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/Sage.html">#</a></span>  

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/Dave-Rogers-on-distracti.html">#</a></span> <blockquote class="quoteback" darkmode="" data-title="Distraction" data-author="" cite="https://nice-marmot.net/">
<p>Somehow, some part of their attention is directed toward the possibility that their application environment isn't "ideal." They have this notion there's some perfect writing environment that will make them more productive or better writers by eliminating this thing called "distraction." There's some anxiety about the tool they're using.</p>
<footer><cite> <a href="https://nice-marmot.net/">https://nice-marmot.net/</a></cite></footer>
</blockquote><script note="" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/Blogger-Peer-Review/quotebacks@1/quoteback.js"></script>
<p>Dave's right. I've gone through many iterations around "distraction-free" writing myself. In my case, though, I don't do it because I feel the writing environment is holding me back. I do it because it can be fun to twiddle with tools. Same with cameras. My cameras have been better than my ability for years, but I still keep trying new cameras because I love cameras.</p>
<p>Oh, and about distraction-free writing in Tinderbox, I wrote <a href="https://archive.baty.net/2012/tinderbox-as-a-minimalist-writing-environment/">Tinderbox as a Minimalist Writing Environment</a> in 2013. (Unfortunately, all of the site's images from 2012 were lost during one of many platform migrations.)</p>
 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/Speaking-of-distractions.html">#</a></span> <p>This week started out with the intention of building a Rails app, but ended with the creation of an entirely new Tinderbox Daybook and blogging system. You're soaking in it. I'm still considering moving the whole enterprise to baty.blog and just living with that for a while. However, I still wonder about returning it to <a href="http://rudimentarylathe.org">rudimentarylathe.org</a> or maybe even replacing the photography domain <a href="http://copingmechanism.com">copingmechanism.com</a>. And who knows, I may end with all of this back in Emacs in a month. But Tinderbox is still super fun and powerful and let's try it!</p>
 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/Note-icons-on-the-archiv.html">#</a></span> <p>Tinderbox does this cool thing in outlines where the icon changes based on the age and size of each note. I'm working on mimicking that feature on the <a href="archives.html">Archives</a> page here. I'm a little lost when it comes to the new "functions" features in Tinderbox 9.1 so I fell back to adding some Action code as an Edict. Like this...</p>

<pre>
if ($TextLength>500) {
    	$NoteIcon="long.png";
}
if ($TextLength>50 & $TextLength<=500) {
    	$NoteIcon ="medium.png";
}
if ($TextLength<50) {
	$NoteIcon ="small.png";
}
if ($Image) {$NoteIcon = "cam.png"};
</pre> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/I-m-going-to-close-this-.html">#</a></span> <blockquote class="quoteback" darkmode="" data-title="I’m Going to Close This Deal Using Business Words I’ve Heard Men Yell in Airports" data-author="@mcsweeneys" cite="https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/im-going-to-close-this-deal-using-business-words-ive-heard-men-yell-in-airports">
<p>Now, we all realize that our jump-off point is agreeing to rally the troops for next quarter so we can circle back to the perfect ROI for the inevitable year-end come-to-Jesus moment. That’s evident from our low-hanging fruit research and the blue-sky white papers presented by the team in marketing, right? NO, YOU’RE WRONG ON THAT, STEVE. STEVE. STEVE. HEAR ME OUT. YOU’RE WRONG. JUST HEAR ME OUT, STEVE.</p>
<footer>@mcsweeneys<cite> <a href="https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/im-going-to-close-this-deal-using-business-words-ive-heard-men-yell-in-airports">https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/im-going-to-close-this-deal-using-business-words-ive-heard-men-yell-in-airports</a></cite></footer>
</blockquote><script note="" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/Blogger-Peer-Review/quotebacks@1/quoteback.js"></script> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/My-everyday-photos-aren-.html">#</a></span> <p>I sometimes attend an event and take deliberate photos with a serious camera. Later, I see shots other people casually snapped with their iPhones or whatever and posted them (with no editing) directly to social media. They're often much better than mine. Am I just wasting my time?</p> 

</div>






<div class="postNoTitle">


<span class="permalinkHash"><a href="posts/2021/12/26/Dan-Brooks-on-our-useles.html">#</a></span> <blockquote class="quoteback" darkmode="" data-title="The Future Is Not Only Useless, It’s Expensive" data-author="@gawker" cite="https://www.gawker.com/culture/the-future-is-useless-expensive">
<p>This is how NFTs make me feel: like the future is useless but expensive, and world-altering technology is now in the hands of a culture so aesthetically and spiritually impoverished that it should maybe go back to telling stories around the cooking fire for a while, just to remember how to mean something.</p>
<footer>@gawker<cite> <a href="https://www.gawker.com/culture/the-future-is-useless-expensive">https://www.gawker.com/culture/the-future-is-useless-expensive</a></cite></footer>
</blockquote><script note="" src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/Blogger-Peer-Review/quotebacks@1/quoteback.js"></script> 

</div>




    ]]></description>
<guid>https://daily.baty.net/posts/2021/12/26.html</guid>
</item>

</channel>

</rss>